<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_bedra_text">
        <item>STEP BY STEP GUIDE \n
1.Assume a press up position so your hands are directly under your chest at shoulder width apart with straight arms \n
2.Your body should form a straight line from your shoulders to your ankles \n
3.Lift your right foot off the floor and slowly raise your knee as close to your chest as you can \n
4.Return to the starting position and repeat with your left leg \n
5.Continue alternating for the desired number of reps or time \n
</item>

        <item>1.For this exercise you will need to use a leg extension machine. First choose your weight and sit on
            the machine with your legs under the pad (feet pointed forward) and the hands holding the side bars. This will be your starting position.
            Tip: You will need to adjust the pad so that it falls on top of your lower leg (just above your feet).
            Also, make sure that your legs form a 90-degree angle between the lower and upper leg. If the angle is less than 90-degrees then that means the knee is over the toes
            which in turn creates undue stress at the knee joint. If the machine is designed that way, either look for another machine or just make sure that
            when you start executing the exercise you stop going down once you hit the 90-degree angle. \n
2.Using your quadriceps, extend your legs to the maximum as you exhale. Ensure that the rest of the body remains stationary on the seat. Pause a second on the contracted position. \n
3.Slowly lower the weight back to the original position as you inhale, ensuring that you do not go past the 90-degree angle limit. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of times. \n </item>

        <item>1.Adjust the machine lever to fit your height and sit on the machine with your back against the back support pad. \n
2.Place the back of lower leg on top of padded lever (just a few inches under the calves) and secure the lap pad against your thighs,
            just above the knees. Then grasp the side handles on the machine as you point your toes straight
            (or you can also use any of the other two stances) and ensure that the legs are fully straight right in front of you.
            This will be your starting position. \n
3.As you exhale, pull the machine lever as far as possible to the back of your thighs by flexing at the knees.
            Keep your torso stationary at all times. Hold the contracted position for a second. \n
4.Slowly return to the starting position as you breathe in. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n </item>

        <item>Stand lunge-length in front of a bench. Hold a dumbbell in each hand and rest the top of your left foot on the bench behind you. \n
            Lower your body until your rear knee nearly touches the floor and your front thigh is parallel to the floor. \n </item>

        <item></item>
        <item>1. Begin with the barbell supported on top of the traps. The chest should be up and the head facing forward. Adopt a hip-width stance with the feet turned out as needed. \n
        2. Descend by flexing the knees, refraining from moving the hips back as much as possible. This requires that the knees travel forward.
            Ensure that they stay align with the feet. The goal is to keep the torso as upright as possible. \n
        3. Continue all the way down, keeping the weight on the front of the heel. At the moment the upper legs contact the lower legs reverse the motion, driving the weight upward. \n </item>

        <item>1.Using a leg press machine, sit down on the machine and place your legs on the platform directly in front of you at a medium (shoulder width)
            foot stance. (Note: For the purposes of this discussion we will use the medium stance described above which targets
            overall development; however you can choose any of the three stances described in the foot positioning section). \n
2.Lower the safety bars holding the weighted platform in place and press the platform all the way up until your legs are fully extended in front of you.
            Tip: Make sure that you do not lock your knees. Your torso and the legs should make a perfect 90-degree angle. This will be your starting position. \n
3.As you inhale, slowly lower the platform until your upper and lower legs make a 90-degree angle. \n
4.Pushing mainly with the heels of your feet and using the quadriceps go back to the starting position as you exhale. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions and ensure to lock the safety pins properly once you are done. You do not want that platform falling on you fully loaded. \n </item>

        <item>1.Approach the bar so that it is centered over your feet. Your feet should be about hip-width apart. Bend at the hip to grip the bar
            at shoulder-width allowing your shoulder blades to protract. Typically, you would use an alternating grip. \n
2.With your feet and your grip set, take a big breath and then lower your hips and flex the knees until your shins contact the bar.
            Look forward with your head. Keep your chest up and your back arched, and begin driving through the heels to move the weight upward. \n
3.After the bar passes the knees aggressively pull the bar back, pulling your shoulder blades together as you drive your hips forward into the bar. \n
4.Lower the bar by bending at the hips and guiding it to the floor. \n </item>
        <item>1.Stand up straight while holding a dumbbell on each hand (palms facing the side of your legs). \n
2.Position your legs using a shoulder width medium stance with the toes slightly pointed out. Keep your head up at all times
            as looking down will get you off balance and also maintain a straight back. This will be your starting position.
            Note: For the purposes of this discussion we will use the medium stance described above which targets overall development;
            however you can choose any of the three stances discussed in the foot stances section. \n
3.Begin to slowly lower your torso by bending the knees as you maintain a straight posture with the head up.
            Continue down until your thighs are parallel to the floor. Tip: If you performed the exercise correctly,
            the front of the knees should make an imaginary straight line with the toes that is perpendicular to the front.
            If your knees are past that imaginary line (if they are past your toes)
            then you are placing undue stress on the knee and the exercise has been performed incorrectly. \n
4.Begin to raise your torso as you exhale by pushing the floor with the heel of your foot mainly as you straighten the legs again and go back to the starting position. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n </item>
        <item>1.Stand with your torso upright holding two dumbbells in your hands by your sides. This will be your starting position. \n
2.Step backward with your right leg around two feet or so from the left foot and lower your upper body down, while keeping the torso upright
            and maintaining balance. Inhale as you go down. Tip: As in the other exercises, do not allow your knee to go
            forward beyond your toes as you come down, as this will put undue stress on the knee joint.
            Make sure that you keep your front shin perpendicular to the ground. Keep the torso upright during the lunge;
            flexible hip flexors are important. A long lunge emphasizes the Gluteus Maximus; a short lunge emphasizes Quadriceps. \n
3.Push up and go back to the starting position as you exhale. Tip: Use the ball of your feet to push in order to accentuate the quadriceps. To focus on the glutes, press with your heels. \n
Now repeat with the opposite leg. \n </item>
        <item>1.Stand with your feet together and your hands down by your side. \n
2.In one motion jump your feet out to the side and raise your arms above your head. \n
3.Immediately reverse that motion by jumping back to the starting position. \n </item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Link: <a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Do-Jump-Squats">http://www.wikihow.com/Do-Jump-Squats</a></item>
        <item>1.First, make sure the athlete’s eyes and head are looking to where they are trying to reach. This will make sure the athlete’s entire body is working to ascend. \n
2.Secondly the athlete’s arm that is reaching upwards should be directly in line with their ear. Too many times athletes will reach too far forward or too far backwards.
            This will throw off balance and shorten the jump. \n
3.Lastly, make sure the athlete is jumping straight up and straight down. This seems obvious, but many times we will see athletes landing
            six inches in either direction of where they started. This means they are sacrificing height for distance, which is obviously not what we want. \n
4.Just by coaching these points, athletes can improve their vertical jump height within minutes.</item>
        <item>1.Begin in a seated, upright position. Start by extending your legs in front of you in a V. \n
2.With your hands on the floor, lean forward as far as possible. Hold for 10 to 20 seconds</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>