<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_bedra_text">
        <item>STEP BY STEP GUIDE \n
1.Assume a press up position so your hands are directly under your chest at shoulder width apart with straight arms \n
2.Your body should form a straight line from your shoulders to your ankles \n
3.Lift your right foot off the floor and slowly raise your knee as close to your chest as you can \n
4.Return to the starting position and repeat with your left leg \n
5.Continue alternating for the desired number of reps or time \n
</item>

        <item>1.For this exercise you will need to use a leg extension machine. First choose your weight and sit on
            the machine with your legs under the pad (feet pointed forward) and the hands holding the side bars. This will be your starting position.
            Tip: You will need to adjust the pad so that it falls on top of your lower leg (just above your feet).
            Also, make sure that your legs form a 90-degree angle between the lower and upper leg. If the angle is less than 90-degrees then that means the knee is over the toes
            which in turn creates undue stress at the knee joint. If the machine is designed that way, either look for another machine or just make sure that
            when you start executing the exercise you stop going down once you hit the 90-degree angle. \n
2.Using your quadriceps, extend your legs to the maximum as you exhale. Ensure that the rest of the body remains stationary on the seat. Pause a second on the contracted position. \n
3.Slowly lower the weight back to the original position as you inhale, ensuring that you do not go past the 90-degree angle limit. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of times. \n </item>

        <item>1.Adjust the machine lever to fit your height and sit on the machine with your back against the back support pad. \n
2.Place the back of lower leg on top of padded lever (just a few inches under the calves) and secure the lap pad against your thighs,
            just above the knees. Then grasp the side handles on the machine as you point your toes straight
            (or you can also use any of the other two stances) and ensure that the legs are fully straight right in front of you.
            This will be your starting position. \n
3.As you exhale, pull the machine lever as far as possible to the back of your thighs by flexing at the knees.
            Keep your torso stationary at all times. Hold the contracted position for a second. \n
4.Slowly return to the starting position as you breathe in. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>