<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_gryb_text">
        <item>1.Using a neutral grip, lean into an incline bench. \n
2.Take a dumbbell in each hand with a neutral grip, beginning with the arms straight. This will be your starting position. \n
3.Retract the shoulder blades and flex the elbows to row the dumbbells to your side. \n
4.Pause at the top of the motion, and then return to the starting position. \n</item>
        <item>1.Position a bar into a landmine or in a corner to keep it from moving. Load an appropriate weight onto your end. \n
2.Stand over the bar, and position a Double D row handle around the bar next to the collar. Using your hips and legs, rise to a standing position. \n
3.Assume a wide stance with your hips back and your chest up. Your arms should be extended. This will be your starting position. \n
4.Pull the weight to your upper abdomen by retracting the shoulder blades and flexing the elbows. Do not jerk the weight or cheat during the movement. \n
5.After a brief pause, return to the starting position. \n</item>
        <item>1.Holding a barbell with a pronated grip (palms facing down), bend your knees slightly
            and bring your torso forward, by bending at the waist, while keeping the back
            straight until it is almost parallel to the floor. Tip: Make sure that you keep the head up.
            The barbell should hang directly in front of you as your arms hang perpendicular to the floor
            and your torso. This is your starting position. \n
2.Now, while keeping the torso stationary, breathe out and lift the barbell to you. Keep the elbows close to the body and only use the forearms to hold the weight.
            At the top contracted position, squeeze the back muscles and hold for a brief pause. \n
3.Then inhale and slowly lower the barbell back to the starting position. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Stand erect while holding a barbell with a supinated grip (palms facing up). \n
2.Bend your knees slightly and bring your torso forward, by bending at the waist, while keeping the back straight until
            it is almost parallel to the floor. Tip: Make sure that you keep the head up. The barbell should hang
            directly in front of you as your arms hang perpendicular to the floor and your torso. This is your starting position. \n
3.While keeping the torso stationary, lift the barbell as you breathe out, keeping the elbows close to the body and not doing any force
            with the forearm other than holding the weights. On the top contracted position, squeeze the back muscles and hold for a second. \n
4.Slowly lower the weight again to the starting position as you inhale. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Place a cambered bar underneath an exercise bench. \n
2.Lie face down on the exercise bench and grab the bar using a palms down (pronated grip) that is wider
            than shoulder width. This will be your starting position. \n
3.As you exhale row the bar up as you keep the elbows close to your body to either your chest, in order
            to target the upper mid back, or to your stomach if targeting the lats is your goal. \n
4.After a second hold at the top, lower back down to the starting position slowly as you inhale. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>