<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_ramo_text">
        <item>1.Sit on an exercise bench with back support and hold two dumbbells in front
            of you at about upper chest level with your palms facing your body and your elbows bent. \n
            Tip: Your arms should be next to your torso. The starting position should look like the
            contracted portion of a dumbbell curl. \n
2.Now to perform the movement, raise the dumbbells as you rotate the palms of
            your hands until they are facing forward. \n
3.Continue lifting the dumbbells until your arms are extended above you in straight arm
            position. Breathe out as you perform this portion of the movement. \n
4.After a second pause at the top, begin to lower the dumbbells to the original position by
            rotating the palms of your hands towards you. Tip: The left arm will be rotated in
            a counter clockwise manner while the right one will be rotated clockwise.
            Breathe in as you perform this portion of the movement. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Start by placing a barbell that is about chest high on a squat rack. Once you have
            selected the weights, grab the barbell using a pronated (palms facing forward) grip.
            Make sure to grip the bar wider than shoulder width apart from each other. \n
2.Slightly bend the knees and place the barbell on your collar bone. Lift the barbell up keeping
            it lying on your chest. Take a step back and position your feet shoulder width
            apart from each other. \n
3.Once you pick up the barbell with the correct grip length, lift the bar up over your head by
            locking your arms. Hold at about shoulder level and slightly in front of your head.
            This is your starting position. \n
4.Lower the bar down to the collarbone slowly as you inhale. \n
5.Lift the bar back up to the starting position as you exhale. \n
6.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>Raise upper arms to sides until elbows are shoulder height.
            Maintain elbows height above or equal to wrists. Lower and repeat.</item>
        <item>1.Pick a couple of dumbbells and stand with a straight torso and the dumbbells on front of your thighs
            at arms length with the palms of the hand facing your thighs. This will be your starting position. \n
2.While maintaining the torso stationary (no swinging), lift the left dumbbell to the front with a slight
            bend on the elbow and the palms of the hands always facing down. Continue to go up until you arm is
            slightly above parallel to the floor. Exhale as you execute this portion of the movement and pause
            for a second at the top. Inhale after the second pause. \n
3.Now lower the dumbbell back down slowly to the starting position as you
            simultaneously lift the right dumbbell. \n
4.Continue alternating in this fashion until all of the recommended amount
            of repetitions have been performed for each arm. \n</item>
        <item>1.Grasp a barbell with an overhand grip that is slightly less than shoulder width.
            The bar should be resting on the top of your thighs with your arms extended and a slight bend in your elbows.
            Your back should also be straight. This will be your starting position. \n
2.Now exhale and use the sides of your shoulders to lift the bar, raising your elbows up and to the side.
            Keep the bar close to your body as you raise it. Continue to lift the bar until it nearly touches your chin.
            Tip: Your elbows should drive the motion, and should always be higher than your forearms. Remember to
            keep your torso stationary and pause for a second at the top of the movement. \n
3.Lower the bar back down slowly to the starting position. Inhale as you perform this portion of the movement. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>Execution \n
Drive hips forward, torso upright, and knees straight so kettlebell is pushed forward and upward.
            Allow kettlebell to swing back down. As kettlebell approaches lower position, fold at hips while
            bending knees. Forearms make contact with inner thighs permitting kettlebell to swing back under hips.
            Immediately repeat movement and continue to swing kettlebell. Maintain shoulder to eye level height swings. \n
Return \n
Swing kettlebell back down between legs. Allow kettlebell to swing forward but do not extend hips and knees (as
            would be required to continue the swing). Slow kettlebells swing and place on floor in original
            deadlift posture. \m</item>
        <item>Preparation \n
Stand with cable columns to each side. Grasp left stirrup with right hand and right stirrup
            with left hand. Bend knees and bend over at hips, so torso is approximately horizontal
            with back straight. Point elbows outward with arms slightly bent. \n
Execution \n
Raise upper arms to sides until elbows are shoulder height. Maintain upper arms perpendicular
            to torso and slight bend in elbows as arms are raised to sides. Lower and repeat. \n</item>
        <!--TODO: ADD info abbout  Peck-Back Machine Shoulder Blades Adduction down-->
        <item>No info abbout this exercise</item>
        <item>1.Sit on a bench with back support in a squat rack. Position a barbell at a height
            that is just above your head. Grab the barbell with a pronated grip (palms facing forward). \n
2.Once you pick up the barbell with the correct grip width, lift the bar up over your head by locking
            your arms. Hold at about shoulder level and slightly in front of your head. This is
            your starting position. \n
3.Lower the bar down to the shoulders slowly as you inhale. \n
4.Lift the bar back up to the starting position as you exhale. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.While holding a dumbbell in each hand, sit on a military press bench or utility bench
            that has back support. Place the dumbbells upright on top of your thighs. \n
2.Now raise the dumbbells to shoulder height one at a time using your thighs to help propel
            them up into position. \n
3.Make sure to rotate your wrists so that the palms of your hands are facing forward. This
            is your starting position. \n
4.Now, exhale and push the dumbbells upward until they touch at the top. \n
5.Then, after a brief pause at the top contracted position, slowly lower the weights
            back down to the starting position while inhaling. \n
6.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>