<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_gryb_text">
        <item>1.Using a neutral grip, lean into an incline bench. \n
2.Take a dumbbell in each hand with a neutral grip, beginning with the arms straight. This will be your starting position. \n
3.Retract the shoulder blades and flex the elbows to row the dumbbells to your side. \n
4.Pause at the top of the motion, and then return to the starting position. \n</item>
        <item>1.Position a bar into a landmine or in a corner to keep it from moving. Load an appropriate weight onto your end. \n
2.Stand over the bar, and position a Double D row handle around the bar next to the collar. Using your hips and legs, rise to a standing position. \n
3.Assume a wide stance with your hips back and your chest up. Your arms should be extended. This will be your starting position. \n
4.Pull the weight to your upper abdomen by retracting the shoulder blades and flexing the elbows. Do not jerk the weight or cheat during the movement. \n
5.After a brief pause, return to the starting position. \n</item>
        <item>1.Holding a barbell with a pronated grip (palms facing down), bend your knees slightly
            and bring your torso forward, by bending at the waist, while keeping the back
            straight until it is almost parallel to the floor. Tip: Make sure that you keep the head up.
            The barbell should hang directly in front of you as your arms hang perpendicular to the floor
            and your torso. This is your starting position. \n
2.Now, while keeping the torso stationary, breathe out and lift the barbell to you. Keep the elbows close to the body and only use the forearms to hold the weight.
            At the top contracted position, squeeze the back muscles and hold for a brief pause. \n
3.Then inhale and slowly lower the barbell back to the starting position. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Stand erect while holding a barbell with a supinated grip (palms facing up). \n
2.Bend your knees slightly and bring your torso forward, by bending at the waist, while keeping the back straight until
            it is almost parallel to the floor. Tip: Make sure that you keep the head up. The barbell should hang
            directly in front of you as your arms hang perpendicular to the floor and your torso. This is your starting position. \n
3.While keeping the torso stationary, lift the barbell as you breathe out, keeping the elbows close to the body and not doing any force
            with the forearm other than holding the weights. On the top contracted position, squeeze the back muscles and hold for a second. \n
4.Slowly lower the weight again to the starting position as you inhale. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Place a cambered bar underneath an exercise bench. \n
2.Lie face down on the exercise bench and grab the bar using a palms down (pronated grip) that is wider
            than shoulder width. This will be your starting position. \n
3.As you exhale row the bar up as you keep the elbows close to your body to either your chest, in order
            to target the upper mid back, or to your stomach if targeting the lats is your goal. \n
4.After a second hold at the top, lower back down to the starting position slowly as you inhale. \n</item>
        <item>1.With a dumbbell in each hand (palms facing your torso), bend your knees slightly and bring your torso
            forward by bending at the waist; as you bend make sure to keep your back straight until it is almost parallel
            to the floor. Tip: Make sure that you keep the head up. The weights should hang directly in front of you as
            your arms hang perpendicular to the floor and your torso. This is your starting position. \n
2.While keeping the torso stationary, lift the dumbbells to your side (as you breathe out), keeping the elbows close
            to the body (do not exert any force with the forearm other than holding the weights).
            On the top contracted position, squeeze the back muscles and hold for a second. \n
3.Slowly lower the weight again to the starting position as you inhale. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Select an appropriate weight and adjust the knee pad to help keep you down. Grasp the
            handle with a pronated grip. This will be your starting position. \n
2.Pull the handle down, squeezing your elbow to your side as you flex the elbow. \n
3.Pause at the bottom of the motion, and then slowly return the handle to the starting position. \n
4.For multiple repetitions, avoid completely returning the weight to keep tension on the muscles being worked. \n</item>
        <item>1.For this exercise you will need access to a low pulley row machine with a V-bar. Note: The V-bar
            will enable you to have a neutral grip where the palms of your hands face each other. To get into the
            starting position, first sit down on the machine and place your feet on the front platform or crossbar
            provided making sure that your knees are slightly bent and not locked. \n
2.Lean over as you keep the natural alignment of your back and grab the V-bar handles. \n
3.With your arms extended pull back until your torso is at a 90-degree angle from your legs. Your back should
            be slightly arched and your chest should be sticking out. You should be feeling a nice stretch on your
            lats as you hold the bar in front of you. This is the starting position of the exercise. \n
4.Keeping the torso stationary, pull the handles back towards your torso while keeping the arms close to it until you
            touch the abdominals. Breathe out as you perform that movement. At that point you should be squeezing your
            back muscles hard. Hold that contraction for a second and slowly go back to the original position while breathing in. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Approach the bar so that it is centered over your feet. Your feet should be about hip-width apart.
            Bend at the hip to grip the bar at shoulder-width allowing your shoulder blades to protract. Typically, you would use an alternating grip. \n
2.With your feet and your grip set, take a big breath and then lower your hips and flex the knees until your shins contact the bar.
            Look forward with your head. Keep your chest up and your back arched, and begin driving through the heels to move the weight upward. \n
3.After the bar passes the knees aggressively pull the bar back, pulling your shoulder blades together as you drive your hips forward into the bar. \n
4.Lower the bar by bending at the hips and guiding it to the floor. \n</item>
       <!-- Pull UPS-->
        <item></item>
        <item>1.You will start by grabbing the wide bar from the top pulley of a pulldown machine and using a wider than
            shoulder-width pronated (palms down) grip. Step backwards two feet or so. \n
2.Bend your torso forward at the waist by around 30-degrees with your arms fully extended in front of you and a slight bend
            at the elbows. If your arms are not fully extended then you need to step a bit more backwards until they are. Once
            your arms are fully extended and your torso is slightly bent at the waist, tighten the lats and then you are ready to begin. \n
3.While keeping the arms straight, pull the bar down by contracting the lats until your hands are next to the side of
            the thighs. Breathe out as you perform this step. \n
4.While keeping the arms straight, go back to the starting position while breathing in. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>SET-UP: Find the pull-down apparatus and a wide grip bar. Attach the bar and adjust
            the knee rests. Take a shoulder-width overhand grip on the bar and establish a tight
            midsection and a neutral spine. \n
LIFT: Pull the bar down until it lightly grazes your chest. Return the weight back to the starting
            position under control. As you pull, cue yourself to push your elbows down, which will
            increase involvement from the lats. \n
EMPHASIS: Do not swing - your back should move very little from the starting position. \n
BENEFITS: The primary target of the pulldown is the latissimus dorsi. While the middle back is also involved
            to a lesser degree in the exercise, the vertical nature of the pull tends to take
            the muscles of the mid back out of the movement. \n</item>
        <item>Facing a high pulley with a rope or dual handles attached, pull the weight directly towards your
            face, separating your hands as you do so. Keep your upper arms parallel to the ground. \n</item>
          <item>1.For this exercise you will need access to a low pulley row machine with a V-bar. Note: The V-bar
            will enable you to have a neutral grip where the palms of your hands face each other. To get into the
            starting position, first sit down on the machine and place your feet on the front platform or crossbar
            provided making sure that your knees are slightly bent and not locked. \n
2.Lean over as you keep the natural alignment of your back and grab the V-bar handles. \n
3.With your arms extended pull back until your torso is at a 90-degree angle from your legs. Your back should
            be slightly arched and your chest should be sticking out. You should be feeling a nice stretch on your
            lats as you hold the bar in front of you. This is the starting position of the exercise. \n
4.Keeping the torso stationary, pull the handles back towards your torso while keeping the arms close to it until you
            touch the abdominals. Breathe out as you perform that movement. At that point you should be squeezing your
            back muscles hard. Hold that contraction for a second and slowly go back to the original position while breathing in. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
<item>1.Place a dumbbell standing up on a flat bench. \n
2.Ensuring that the dumbbell stays securely placed at the top of the bench, lie perpendicular to the bench
    (torso across it as in forming a cross) with only your shoulders lying on the surface. Hips should be
    below the bench and legs bent with feet firmly on the floor. The head will be off the bench as well. \n
3.Grasp the dumbbell with both hands and hold it straight over your chest at arms length. Both palms should
    be pressing against the underside one of the sides of the dumbbell. This will be your starting position. \n
Caution: Always ensure that the dumbbell used for this exercise is secure. Using a dumbbell with loose plates
    can result in the dumbbell falling apart and falling on your face. \n

4.While keeping your arms straight, lower the weight slowly in an arc behind your head while breathing
    in until you feel a stretch on the chest. \n
5.At that point, bring the dumbbell back to the starting position using the arc through which
    the weight was lowered and exhale as you perform this movement. \n
6.Hold the weight on the initial position for a second and repeat the motion for the prescribed
    number of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie face down on a hyperextension bench, tucking your ankles securely under the footpads. \n
2.Adjust the upper pad if possible so your upper thighs lie flat across the wide pad, leaving
            enough room for you to bend at the waist without any restriction. \n
3.With your body straight, cross your arms in front of you (my preference) or behind your head. This
            will be your starting position. Tip: You can also hold a weight plate for extra resistance
            in front of you under your crossed arms. \n
4.Start bending forward slowly at the waist as far as you can while keeping your back flat. Inhale as
            you perform this movement. Keep moving forward until you feel a nice stretch on the hamstrings
            and you can no longer keep going without a rounding of the back. Tip: Never round the back as
            you perform this exercise. Also, some people can go farther than others. The key thing is that
            you go as far as your body allows you to without rounding the back. \n
5.Slowly raise your torso back to the initial position as you inhale. Tip: Avoid the temptation to arch your
            back past a straight line. Also, do not swing the torso at any time in order to protect the back from injury. \n
6.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>Dissolution of heat-insulating backing machine is pulling exercise that can be performed
            ednostavno and mnogostavno. Under terms of performance influenced to varying degrees on the
            rear shoulder muscles, upper outer and inner middle sector back. Exercise is crucial for both
            the table and the tone of rear shoulder heads and strength, stamina and power balance of the entire
            shoulder girdle and particularly of the posterior adductor. The technique is suitable for intermediate
            and advanced exercisers. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>