<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_korem_text">
        <item>Instructions /n
Preparation /n
On floor or mat, place exercise ball between lower legs. Lie on back with arms extended out to sides.
            Raise legs upward with knees slightly bent. \n
Execution \n
Lower legs to one side until side of thigh is on floor. Raise and lower legs to opposite side. \n
            Repeat. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie flat on the floor with the lower back pressed into the ground and arms extended behind your legs /n
2.The back of the shoulders should touch the floor and the palms face the ceiling /n
3.Keep the feet together and the toes pointed at the ceiling /n
4.In one movement lift the legs up keeping them straight and raise the upper body of
            the floor reaching for the toes with your hands \n
5.Engage and squeeze the abdominal muscles as you reach for your toes \n
6.Slowly lower the body back down to the starting position \n</item>
        <item>Step 1 /n
Lie on the bench with your legs raised up in the air. /n
Step 2 /n
Press your hips off of the bench and drive your legs into the air. /n
Step 3 /n
Lower your body back down on to the bench and repeat. /n</item>
        <item>No info take a look to picture and watch video /n</item>
        <item>The sit-up is an abdominal endurance training exercise commonly
            performed to strengthen and tone the abdominal muscles. It is similar
            to a crunch (crunches target the rectus abdominus and also work the external
            and internal obliques), but sit-ups have a fuller range of motion and condition
            additional muscles. Sit-ups target the hip flexors, rectus abdominus and also
            work the iliopsoas, tensor fasciae latae, rectus femoris, sartorius, .....and,
            to a very small degree, the obliques.</item>
        <item>Lie facedown with legs extended and elbows bent and directly under shoulders;
            clasp your hands. Feet should be hip-width apart, and elbows should be shoulder-width
            apart. Contract your abs, then tuck your toes to lift your body (forearms remain on the ground);
            you should be in a straight line from head to heels. Hold for 60 seconds or as long as you can.</item>
        <item>1.Kneel below a high pulley that contains a rope attachment. /n
2.Grasp cable rope attachment and lower the rope until your hands are placed next to your face. \n
3.Flex your hips slightly and allow the weight to hyperextend the lower back. This will be your starting position. \n
4.With the hips stationary, flex the waist as you contract the abs so that the elbows travel towards the middle of
            the thighs. Exhale as you perform this portion of the movement and hold the contraction for a second. \n
5.Slowly return to the starting position as you inhale. Tip: Make sure that you keep constant tension on the abs throughout
            the movement. Also, do not choose a weight so heavy that the lower back handles the brunt of the work. \n
6.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie down on the floor placing your feet either under something that will not move
            or by having a partner hold them. Your legs should be bent at the knees. \n
2.Elevate your upper body so that it creates an imaginary V-shape with your thighs. Your arms should
            be fully extended in front of you perpendicular to your torso and with the hands clasped.
            This is the starting position. \n
3.Twist your torso to the right side until your arms are parallel with the floor while breathing out. \n
4.Hold the contraction for a second and move back to the starting position while breathing out. Now move
            to the opposite side performing the same techniques you applied to the right side. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Hold the Ab Roller with both hands and kneel on the floor. /n
2.Now place the ab roller on the floor in front of you so that you are on all your hands
            and knees (as in a kneeling push up position). This will be your starting position. \n
3.Slowly roll the ab roller straight forward, stretching your body into a straight position. Tip: Go down
            as far as you can without touching the floor with your body. Breathe in during this portion of the movement. /n
4.After a pause at the stretched position, start pulling yourself back to the starting position as you breathe out.
            Tip: Go slowly and keep your abs tight at all times.</item>
        <item>No info take a look to picture and watch video /n</item>
        <item>1.Select a light resistance and sit down on the ab machine placing your feet under the pads provided
            and grabbing the top handles. Your arms should be bent at a 90 degree angle as you rest the triceps on the
            pads provided. This will be your starting position. \n
2.At the same time, begin to lift the legs up as you crunch your upper torso. Breathe out as you perform this movement.
            Tip: Be sure to use a slow and controlled motion. Concentrate on using your abs to move the weight while relaxing
            your legs and feet. \n
3.After a second pause, slowly return to the starting position as you breathe in. \n
5.Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>