<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_triceps_text">
        <item>1.Grab a dumbbell and either sit on a military press bench or a utility bench that has
            a back support on it as you place the dumbbells upright on top of your thighs or stand up straight. \n
2.Clean the dumbbell up to bring it to shoulder height and then extend the arm over your head
            so that the whole arm is perpendicular to the floor and next to your head. The dumbbell
            should be on top of you. The other hand can be kept fully extended to the side, by the waist,
            supporting the upper arm that has the dumbbell or grabbing a fixed surface. \n
3.Rotate the wrist so that the palm of your hand is facing forward and the pinkie is facing
            the ceiling. This will be your starting position. \n
4.Slowly lower the dumbbell behind your head as you hold the upper arm stationary.
            Inhale as you perform this movement and pause when your triceps are fully stretched. \n
5.Return to the starting position by flexing your triceps as you breathe out. /n
            Tip: It is imperative that only the forearm moves. The upper arm should
            remain at all times stationary next to your head. \n
6.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions and switch arms. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie back on a flat bench. Using a close grip (around shoulder width), lift the bar from
            the rack and hold it straight over you with your arms locked. This will be your starting position. \n
2.As you breathe in, come down slowly until you feel the bar on your middle chest. Tip: Make sure that - as opposed
            to a regular bench press - you keep the elbows close to the torso at all times in order to maximize
            triceps involvement. \n
3.After a second pause, bring the bar back to the starting position as you breathe out and push the bar using
            your triceps muscles. Lock your arms in the contracted position, hold for a second and then start
            coming down slowly again. Tip: It should take at least twice as long to go down than to come up. \n
4.Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions. \n
5.When you are done, place the bar back in the rack. \n</item>
        <item>1.Start with a dumbbell in each hand and your palms facing your torso.
            Keep your back straight with a slight bend in the knees and bend forward at the waist.
            Your torso should be almost parallel to the floor. Make sure to keep your head up.
            Your upper arms should be close to your torso and parallel to the floor. Your forearms
            should be pointed towards the floor as you hold the weights. There should be a 90-degree
            angle formed between your forearm and upper arm. This is your starting position. \n
2.Now, while keeping your upper arms stationary, exhale and use your triceps
            to lift the weights until the arm is fully extended. Focus on moving the forearm. \n
3.After a brief pause at the top contraction, inhale and slowly
            lower the dumbbells back down to the starting position. \n
4.Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.To get into the starting position, hold your body at arms length
            with your arms nearly locked above the bars. \n
2.Now, inhale and slowly lower yourself downward. Your torso should remain upright
            and your elbows should stay close to your body. This helps to better focus on
            tricep involvement. Lower yourself until there is a 90 degree angle formed
            between the upper arm and forearm. \n
3.Then, exhale and push your torso back up using your triceps to bring
            your body back to the starting position. \n
4.Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.For this exercise you will need to place a bench behind your back.
            With the bench perpendicular to your body, and while looking away from it,
            hold on to the bench on its edge with the hands fully extended, separated at shoulder
            width. The legs will be extended forward, bent at the waist and perpendicular to your torso.
            This will be your starting position. \n
2.Slowly lower your body as you inhale by bending at the elbows until you lower yourself far enough to
            where there is an angle slightly smaller than 90 degrees between the upper arm and the forearm. \n
            Tip: Keep the elbows as close as possible throughout the movement. Forearms should always be pointing down. \n
3.Using your triceps to bring your torso up again, lift yourself back to the starting position. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.To get into the starting position, hold your body at arms length
            with your arms nearly locked above the bars. \n
2.Now, inhale and slowly lower yourself downward. Your torso should remain upright
            and your elbows should stay close to your body. This helps to better focus on
            tricep involvement. Lower yourself until there is a 90 degree angle formed
            between the upper arm and forearm. \n
3.Then, exhale and push your torso back up using your triceps to bring
            your body back to the starting position. \n
4.Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie on the floor face down and place your hands about 36 inches
            apart while holding your torso up at arms length. \n
2.Next, lower yourself downward until your chest almost touches the
            floor as you inhale. \n
3.Now breathe out and press your upper body back up to the starting position
            while squeezing your chest. \n
4.After a brief pause at the top contracted position, you can begin to lower
            yourself downward again for as many repetitions as needed. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie on the floor face down and place your hands closer than shoulder width for
            a close hand position. Make sure that you are holding your torso up at arms length. \n
2.Lower yourself until your chest almost touches the floor as you inhale. \n
3.Using your triceps and some of your pectoral muscles, press your upper body back up to the starting
            position and squeeze your chest. Breathe out as you perform this step. \n
4.After a second pause at the contracted position, repeat the movement for the prescribed amount
            of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie on the floor face down and place your hands closer than shoulder width for
            a close hand position. Make sure that you are holding your torso up at arms length. \n
2.Lower yourself until your chest almost touches the floor as you inhale. \n
3.Using your triceps and some of your pectoral muscles, press your upper body back up to the starting
            position and squeeze your chest. Breathe out as you perform this step. \n
4.After a second pause at the contracted position, repeat the movement for the prescribed amount
            of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Place a dumbbell standing up on a flat bench. \n
2.Ensuring that the dumbbell stays securely placed at the top of the bench, lie perpendicular
            to the bench with only your shoulders lying on the surface. Hips should be below
            the bench and your legs bent with your feet firmly on the floor. \n
3.Grasp the dumbbell with both hands and hold it straight over your chest at arm’s length.
            Both palms should be pressing against the underside of the sides of the dumbbell.
            This will be your starting position. \n
4.Initiate the movement by lowering the dumbbell to your chest. \n
5.Return to the starting position by extending the elbows. \n</item>
        <item>1.Attach a straight or angled bar to a high pulley and grab with an overhand
            grip (palms facing down) at shoulder width. \n
2.Standing upright with the torso straight and a very small inclination forward, bring the upper
            arms close to your body and perpendicular to the floor. The forearms should be pointing
            up towards the pulley as they hold the bar. This is your starting position. \n
3.Using the triceps, bring the bar down until it touches the front of your thighs and the arms are fully
            extended perpendicular to the floor. The upper arms should always remain stationary next to
            your torso and only the forearms should move. Exhale as you perform this movement. \n
4.After a second hold at the contracted position, bring the bar slowly up to the starting point. Breathe
            in as you perform this step. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie on a flat bench while holding two dumbbells directly in front of you. Your
            arms should be fully extended at a 90-degree angle from your torso and the floor. The
            palms should be facing in and the elbows should be tucked in. This is the starting position. \n
2.As you breathe in and you keep the upper arms stationary with the elbows in, slowly lower the weight
            until the dumbbells are near your ears. \n
3.At that point, while keeping the elbows in and the upper arms stationary, use the triceps to bring the
            weight back up to the starting position as you breathe out. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Lie on a flat bench with feet on the ground and head hanging just off the top of the bench,
            so that the edge of the bench rests in the pit between neck and head. \n
2.Take the barbell with an overhand grip (palms away from body) and hold it out above the head so that the
            arms are supporting the weight. Do not hold the arms straight over the face at 12  clock, but rather
            at an angle more like 10 clock, with feet at 3  clock. All of the weight should be on the triceps. \n
3.Now bend the arms at the elbow, bringing the bar down close to the top of the forehead. \n
4.Keep the elbows in the same position, do not let them sway outward. \n
5.Press back up to starting 10 o’clock position. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>