<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_predmishnici_text">
        <item>1.Stand up with your torso upright while holding a barbell at shoulder width
            with the elbows close to the torso. The palm of your hands should be facing down
            (pronated grip). This will be your starting position. \n
2.While holding the upper arms stationary, curl the weights while contracting the biceps as you
            breathe out. Only the forearms should move. Continue the movement until your biceps
            are fully contracted and the bar is at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position
            for a second as you squeeze the muscle. \n
3.Slowly begin to bring the bar back to starting position as your breathe in. \n
4.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Sit on a flat bench with a dumbbell in your right hand. \n
2.Place your feet flat on the floor, at a distance that is slightly wider
            than shoulder width apart. \n
3.Lean forward and place your right forearm on top of your upper right thigh with
            your palm down. Tip: Make sure that the back of the wrist lies on top
            of your knees. This will be your starting position. \n
4.Lower the dumbbell as far as possible as you keep a tight grip on the dumbbell.
            Inhale as you perform this movement. \n
5.Now curl the dumbbell as high as possible as you contract the forearms and as you exhale.
            Keep the contraction for a second before you lower again. Tip: The only movement should happen at the wrist. \n
5.Perform for the recommended amount of repetitions, switch arms and repeat the movement. \n</item>
        <item>Lateral movement away from the midline of the body; moving the thumb side
            of the hand toward the lateral side of the forearm. \n</item>
        <item>1.Start out by placing two dumbbells on the floor in front of a flat bench. \n
2.Sit down on the edge of the flat bench with your legs at about shoulder width apart.
            Make sure to keep your feet on the floor. \n
3.Use your arms to grab both of the dumbbells and bring them up so that your forearms
            are resting against your thighs with the palms of the hands facing up.
            Your wrists should be hanging over the edge of your thighs. \n
4.Start out by curling your wrist upwards and exhaling. \n
5.Slowly lower your wrists back down to the starting position while inhaling. Make sure
            to inhale during this part of the exercise. Tip: Your forearms should be
            stationary as your wrist is the only movement needed to perform this exercise. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n
6.When finished, simply lower the dumbbells to the floor. \n</item>
        <item>1.Stand up with your torso upright and a dumbbell on each hand being held at arms
            length. The elbows should be close to the torso. \n
2.The palms of the hands should be facing your torso. This will be your starting position. \n
3.Now, while holding your upper arm stationary, exhale and curl the weight forward while contracting
            the biceps. Continue to raise the weight until the biceps are fully contracted and the dumbbell
            is at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a brief moment as you squeeze the biceps.
            Tip: Focus on keeping the elbow stationary and only moving your forearm. \n
4.After the brief pause, inhale and slowly begin the lower the dumbbells back down to the starting position. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>