<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exercises_prasec_text">
        <item>Instructions /n
Preparation /n
Place shoulders under padded lever. Position toes and balls of feet
            on calf block with arches and heels extending off. Grasp
            handles or sides of padded lever. Stand erect by extending hips and knees. \n
Execution \n
Raise heels by extending ankles as high as possible. Lower heels by bending
            ankles until calves are stretched.\n
            Repeat. \n</item>
        <item>1.Using a leg press machine, sit down on the machine and place your legs on the platform directly
            in front of you at a medium (shoulder width) foot stance. \n
2.Lower the safety bars holding the weighted platform in place and press the platform all
            the way up until your legs are fully extended in front of you without locking your knees.
            (Note: In some leg press units you can leave the safety bars on for increased safety. If
            your leg press unit allows for this, then this is the preferred method of performing the exercise.)
            Your torso and the legs should make perfect 90-degree angle. Now carefully place your toes and balls
            of your feet on the lower portion of the platform with the heels extending off. Toes should be facing
            forward, outwards or inwards as described at the beginning of the chapter. This will be your starting position. \n
3.Press on the platform by raising your heels as you breathe out by extending your ankles as high as possible and
            flexing your calf. Ensure that the knee is kept stationary at all times. There should be no bending
            at any time. Hold the contracted position by a second before you start to go back down. \n
4.Go back slowly to the starting position as you breathe in by lowering your heels as you bend
            the ankles until calves are stretched. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Adjust the padded lever of the calf raise machine to fit your height. \n
2.Place your shoulders under the pads provided and position your toes facing forward (or using any
            of the two other positions described at the beginning of the chapter). The balls of
            your feet should be secured on top of the calf block with the heels extending off it.
            Push the lever up by extending your hips and knees until your torso is standing erect.
            The knees should be kept with a slight bend; never locked. Toes should be facing forward,
            outwards or inwards as described at the beginning of the chapter. This will be your starting
            position. \n
3.Raise your heels as you breathe out by extending your ankles as high as possible and flexing your calf.
            Ensure that the knee is kept stationary at all times. There should be no bending at any time.
            Hold the contracted position by a second before you start to go back down. \n
4.Go back slowly to the starting position as you breathe in by lowering your heels as you bend the
            ankles until calves are stretched. \n
5.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. \n</item>
        <item>1.Stand with your feet together and your hands down by your side. \n
2.In one motion jump your feet out to the side and raise your arms above your head. \n
3.Immediately reverse that motion by jumping back to the starting position. \n</item>
        <item>TECHNIQUE \n
1.Stand in an athletic position, with your feet shoulder-width apart, at a comfortable distance from the box. \n
2.When you’re ready to jump, drop quickly into a quarter squat, then extend your hips, swing your arms, and push
            your feet through the floor to propel yourself onto the box. \n
            3.Don’t “stick” your landing. Instead, envision the way cats land when they jump from something—you,
            too, should try to land this quietly. \n</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>